131method.com 2019-04-03

# Website Privacy Policy - The 131 Method

Your privacy is important to 131method.com.  Please read this privacy notice carefully as it contains important information on who we are, how and why we collect, store, use, and share personal information, your rights in relation to your personal information and on how to contact us and supervisory authorities in the event you have a complaint.

## 1\. Who We Are

Smartlife Inc., doing business as 131 METHOD collects, uses and is responsible for certain personal information about you.

## 2\. Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act

This website and any products and services offered herein are not intended for persons under the age of 13. 131method.com does not knowingly collect information from anyone under 13 years of age. 131method.com prohibits children under the age of 13 from using all interactive portions of this website, including leaving any comments, filling out forms, or otherwise submitting information. 131method.com will not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. If 131method.com learns it has any information or content from anyone under the age of 13, it will delete that information.

## 3\. The Personal Information We Collect and Use

### a. Information Collected by Us

131method.com may collect, use, and is responsible for certain personal information that you provide when you voluntarily order a service or product, fill out any type of form, sign up for emails or free gifts, attend an event, register for a webinar, leave comments, access private membership pages, or otherwise contact 131method.com via an online form or email. The information collected may include your name, e-mail, address, phone number, and/or billing information. You are not required to provide any personally identifiable information to merely access or visit this website.

131method.com may collect domain information and “cookies” (small files saved on your hard drive by your web browser) to analyze website performance, track user patterns, save information from your previous visits and customize your experience. We will ask for your consent to allow us to use cookies.  131method.com or its third-party vendors may collect nonpersonal information through the use of these technologies. Nonpersonal information might include the browser you use, the type of computer you use and technical information about your means of connection to this website such as the operating systems and the Internet service providers utilized and other similar information. 131method.com’s systems may also automatically gather information about the areas you visit and search terms you use on this website and about the links you may select from within this website to other areas of the Internet.

If you are located in the European Economic Area (EEA), we are regulated under the General Data Protection Regulation which applies across the European Union (including in the United Kingdom) and we are responsible as controller of that personal information for the purposes of those laws.

### b. How we use your personal information

131method.com collects such information in order to send e-mails, fulfill orders, deliver services and products, complete customer transactions, oversee contests and promotions and improve website performance and customer service.

### c. Who We Share Your Personal Information With

131method.com respects your privacy and will never sell, trade or transfer your personally identifiable information to third parties (beyond what is necessary for fulfilling a customer transaction or for the basic functionality of an online service) without your consent. We do, however, share your name and delivery address details with our third-party suppliers, credit card processors or shipping companies. For a list of our third-party suppliers  see link. This data sharing enables them to deliver the goods you ordered directly to you. Those third-party recipients are based outside the European Economic Area. For further information including on how we safeguard your personal data when this occurs, see Transfer of your information out of the EEA.

131method.com may release personal information to enforce its Website Terms and Conditions of Use, other Terms and Conditions, manage its business, protect users or the general public, or to otherwise comply with legal obligations.

If you give 131method.com your permission, it may also use personal identification information for internal or external marketing and promotional purposes.

On occasion, 131method.com may collect personal identification information from you in connection with optional contests, special offers or promotions. 131method.com will share such information with necessary third parties for the purpose of carrying out the contest, special offer or promotion. We will ask for your consent to such disclosure and use of such information, prior to your participation in the contest, special offer or promotion.

We will not share your personal information with any other third party.

### d. Whether Information Has to Be Provided by You and Why

We do not require you to provide any personal data in order to view our website. We will inform you when we collect it whether you are required to provide the information to us.

### e. How Long Your Personal Information Will Be Kept

We will hold name, address, and contact details)] for 6 years.

### f. Reasons We Can Collect and Use Your Personal Information

131method.com collects and uses your personal information to send emails, fulfill orders, deliver services and products, complete customer transactions, oversee contests and promotions and improve website performance and customer service.

## 4\. Use and Transfer of Your Information Out of the EEA

This website is operated in the United States and third parties with whom we might share your personal information as explained above are also located in the United States.  If you are located in the EEA or elsewhere outside of the United States, please be aware that **any information you provide will be transferred to the United States.** By using this website, participating in any of its services and/or providing your information, you consent to this transfer.

These countries do not have the same data protection laws as the United Kingdom and EEA. While the European Commission has not given a formal decision that the United States provide an adequate level of data protection similar to those which apply in the United Kingdom and EEA, any transfer of your personal information will be subject to a European Commission approved contract as permitted under, Article 46(5) full text here: [https://gdpr-info.eu](https://gdpr-info.eu/) of the General Data Protection Regulation that are designed to help safeguard your privacy rights and give you remedies in the unlikely event of a misuse of your personal information.

If you would like further information, (see “How to contact us” below.  We will not otherwise transfer your personal data outside of the United Kingdom OR EEA or to any organization (or subordinate bodies) governed by public international law or which is set up under any agreement between two or more countries.

## 5\. Your Rights

If you want to unsubscribe from receiving emails from 131method.com, you may do so at any time. Each email from 131method.com includes instructions for unsubscribing from these e-mail communications.

If you are covered by the General Data Protection Regulation, you have a number of important rights free of charge. In summary, those include rights to:

  * Fair processing of information and transparency over how we use your use personal information
  * Access to your personal information and to certain other supplementary information that this Privacy Notice is already designed to address
  * Require us to correct any mistakes in your information which we hold
  * Require the erasure of personal information concerning you in certain situations
  * Receive the personal information concerning you which you have provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and have the right to transmit those data to a third party in certain situations
  * Object at any time to processing of personal information concerning you for direct marketing
  * Object to decisions being taken by automated means which produce legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affect you
  * Object in certain other situations to our continued processing of your personal information
  * Otherwise restrict our processing of your personal information in certain circumstances

You may also have the right to claim compensation for damages caused by our breach of any data protection laws.

For further information on each of those rights, including the circumstances in which they apply, see the Guidance from the UK Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) on individuals’ rights under the General Data Protection Regulation, available at: <https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/> .

If you would like to exercise any of those rights, please:

  * Email, call, or write to us
  * Provide us enough information to identify you (e.g., user name, e-mail address, registration details)
  * Provide us proof of your identity and address (a copy of your driver’s license or passport and a recent utility or credit card bill)
  * Provide us with the information to which your request relates

## 6\. Keeping Your Personal Information Secure

We have appropriate security measures in place to prevent personal information from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorized way. We limit access to your personal information to those who have a genuine business need to know it. Those processing your information will do so only in an authorized manner and are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We also have procedures in place to deal with any suspected data security breach. We will notify you and any applicable authorities of a suspected data security breach where we are legally required to do so.

Please note that any comments or information that you post on the website, including the 131method.com membership site and social media pages, become public and third parties may use your information. 131method.com is not responsible for any unauthorized uses by third parties in such context. You disclose such information at your own risk.

## 7\. Links to Other Sites

You may see advertising or other content on this website that links to the sites and services of our partners, suppliers, advertisers, sponsors, licensors or other third parties.  Any products or services reached through a third-party link are subject to separate privacy policies. 131method.com is not responsible for or liable for any content on or actions taken by such third-party websites.

## 8\. How to Complain

We hope that we can resolve any question or concern you raise about our use of your information.

If you are covered by the General Data Protection Regulation, you may lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, in particular in the European Union (or European Economic Area) state where you work, normally live, or where any alleged infringement of data protection laws occurred.

## 9\. Changes to This Privacy Notice

This policy is effective as of 10/2018.  We may change, modify or update this Privacy Policy at any time and will notify you of any such changes by email or postal mail.

## 10\. How to Contact Us

If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, the information we hold about you, or you wish to change your personal information in our records, please contact Allyson Call, Customer Service Manager, [customerservice@131method.com](mailto:customerservice@131method.com), 51 Vantis Drive, Aliso Viejo, CA 92656

## 11\. Do You Need Extra Help?

If you would like this notice in another format (for example: audio, large print, braille) please contact us (see “How to contact us” above).
